기어다녀!
엠마가 기어다녀!
She's crawling! Emma's crawling!
피가 나!
조이가 피가 나!
He's bleeding! Joey's bleeding!
미안해, 와서 이것좀 봐
모니카랑 챈들러도 불러야지
I'm sorry. You've gotta see this.
I'm gonna go get Monica and Chandler.
모니카! 챈들러!
Monica! Chandler!
건너와! 건너와!
빨리! 빨리! 빨리!
Come over! Come over!
Hurry up! Hurry up! Hurry up!
왜? 왜?
What? What?
- 면도 하냐?
- 아니, 광견병이야
- Shaving?
- No, rabies.
- 왜그래?
- 엠마가 기어다녀
- What's going on?
- It's Emma. She's crawling.
와, 정말이네
Wow, look at her go.
조금만 기다려봐
Give her a second.
이렇게 빨리 자라다니
내 무릎에 앉아서 방귀 뀌던게
I can't believe how fast she's growing up.
It seems like only yesterday she was..
바로 어제 같은데 말야
farting on my lap.
당해보니깐 기분 별로지?
Not so funny when someone
does that to you, is it?
엠마, 기어봐
아까한거 다시 보여줘봐
Emma, come on. Show everybody
how you were crawling.
우리가 방해되나봐
움직이지 말고 가만히 있어보자
I think we're distracting her.
Let's everybody be still for a minute.
누가 우릴 그리는 거야?
Who's painting us?
프렌즈 시즌 9
'성형수술'
우리 은행잔고 봤어?
이게 맞는거야?
Have you seen our bank statement?
Can this be right?
글쎄 말야, 저금한 돈
다 까먹어 보긴 처음이야
I know. God, I haven't seen
my savings take a hit like this..
옛날에 크림이 두배 많은
오레오 과자 나왔을때 빼고
since I was a kid and they came up
with Double Stuf Oreos.
- 우리 돈 다 어디 간거야?
- 잘은 모르지만 분명히
- What happened to all of our money?
- I'm not sure exactly what they did..
엔론 사태 때문일 거야
but I'm inclined to blame Enron.
자기가 인턴 사원이라
버는 것보다 쓰는게 많아서 그런거지
With you doing the internship, we're
spending more than we're bringing in.
인턴 그만두고 돈되는 직업
구해야 할까봐
Yeah, maybe I should quit
and get a job that pays.
마침내 자기가
좋아하는 일을 찾았잖아!
But you're finally doing something
that you love.
그걸 포기하라고 할순 없어!
I mean, I can't ask you to give that up.
자기가 좋아하는 일이
황금 찾기였다면 훨씬 좋았겠지만
Although it would be nice if the thing
that you loved was finding gold.
우리 너무 심각하게
생각하는것 같아
You know, I think we're making
too big a deal out of this.
이번달 공과금은 조금 늦게 내자구
다음달엔 지출을 좀 줄이는 거야
We'll pay our bills late this month. Next
month we'll cut back on a few things.
이제부턴 우리가 조이네
냉장고에서 식사를 해결하자
And maybe we start eating
out of Joey's refrigerator for a change.
자기 요리사지? 베이킹 소다랑
맥주로 뭘 만들수 있어?
You're a chef. What can you make
out of baking soda and beer?
최악의 경우엔 우리 부모님한테
돈을 좀 빌리자
Worst-case scenario is, we borrow
some money from my parents.
아니면, 자기 지난달에
부모님 댁에서
Or, you slipped on ice at their house
last month. Can we sue them?
얼음에 미끄러졌잖아
고소해버릴까?
아니, 돈은 절대 안빌려
No, and we're not borrowing money.
- 왜?
- 우린 그렇게 살지 않아!
- Why not?
- We don't do that. We are Bings.
우리는 빙 부부라구!
아버지가 딱 한가지
가르쳐 주신게 있다면
If there's one thing my father
taught me, it was..
당구대 있는 방에 들어갈땐
항상 노크를 하라는 거였지만
well, to always knock
before going into the pool house.
또 한가지는 절대
돈을 빌리지 말라는 거였어
- The other thing is, never borrow money.
- I had no idea you had this much pride.
와, 그렇게 자존심이
강한줄 몰랐는데?
맞아! 난 자존심이 강해!
나만 믿어! 내가 다 해결할게!
That's right, I do. I am your man.
I'm gonna get us through this situation..
자기가 두배로 일하면 돼!
even if it means you working
twice as hard.
참 이상하죠?
You know, it's just really weird.
자기는 동물을 먹는건
싫어하면서
You don't like eating animals, but you love
watching them tear each other apart.
동물들끼리 뜯어먹는걸
보는걸 좋아하니
그게 아니에요..
쟬 잡아!
No, I don't.. Get him. Get him!
아픈놈을 무리에서 떼어내!
Separate the sick one from the herd!
- 가야겠어요
- 왜요?
- I'm gonna go.
- Why?
며칠째 집에 못가서
옷을 더 가져 와야해요
I haven't been home in days,
and I need to get more clothes.
그럴필요 없어요
마이크가 입을 만한 옷 있어요
You don't have to go.
I have something that'll fit you.
그 탱크톱은 장난삼아
입어본 거예요
I put that tube top on as a joke.
- 가지 말아요
- 나도 여기 있고 싶어요
- I want you to stay.
- I want to stay too.
하지만 지금 입은 팬티로
해볼건 다 해봤다고요
But I've got as much use
out of these boxers as I can.
- 뒤집어 입어..
- 그것도 했어요
- Why don't you turn them inside..
- Done it.
- 두시간 안에 올게요
- 보고싶을 거예요
- I'll be back in a couple of hours.
- All right. I'll miss you.
나도
Me too.
용하게 안잡혔네
Oh, fine. Yeah, you got away.
긴장 풀지마
곧 피를 볼테니깐
But don't look so smug.
You're gonna bleed to death.
그거 알아요? 생각해보니까
나 집에 가기 싫어요
You know what? I just realized something.
I don't want to go home.
좋아요! 얼른 내 탱크톱
갖다 줄게요!
- Great! Okay, I'll go get the tube top.
- No, no, what I mean is..
아니, 내말은..
이젠 내 아파트로
다시 돌아가기 싫어요
I hate going back
to my apartment now.
그 구질구질한 구석으로
들어가는 것도 싫지만
Partly because I live above
a known crack den..
그보다 거기가면
피비가 너무 그리워요
but, you know, mostly because
when I'm there, I really miss you.
그래서 말인데..
So..
우리 같이 살까요?
do you want to move in together?
오, 마이크 해니건!
Wow, Mike Hanigan..
여자가 거절 못하게 하는법을
잘 아네요! "네, 좋아요!"
you sure know how to
make a girl say "Hell, yeah."
- 정말이에요?
- 그래요! 같이 살아요!
- So we're doing it?
- Yeah, let's do it. Let's live together.
- 우리 정말 동거하는 건가요?
- 네
- We're really gonna move in together?
- Yeah.
남자랑 동거해보고 싶었어요
I've always wanted to live with a guy.
양말 주워요!
변기 뚜껑좀 내려!
Pick up your socks.
Put down the toilet seat.
안돼! 내몸에 손대지마!
No, we are not having sex anymore.
재미있겠다!
It's gonna be fun.
TV가이드, 창피한줄 알아!
Shame on you, TV Guide.
남자 엉덩이 보이는게
노출이니?
A man's ass is not nudity!
- 조이?
- 안녕
- Hey, Joey.
- Hey.
지금 내가 부탁하려는거
Listen, I need to know
that what I'm about to ask you..
챈들러한테는 절대로
말하면 안돼
will never get back to Chandler.
이런일 생각해본적 없다고
한다면 거짓말이겠지
I'd be lying if I said I hadn't
thought about it myself.
하지만 난 챈들러 친구야
우리 그러면 안돼
But Chandler is my best friend.
It would be wrong.
좋긴 하겠지만
그럼 못써
Good, but wrong.
그냥 좋은게 아니라
기막히게 좋을걸?
Okay, first of all, it would be great.
하지만 내가 부탁하려는건
그게 아냐, 나 돈좀 빌려줘
But that's not what I'm here to talk
to you about. I need to borrow money.
그건 곤란한데..
친구들 사이엔
Oh, I don't know, Monica.
You know..
돈 빌려주는게 아냐
lending friends money
is always a mistake.
- 챈들러는 너한테 돈 빌려줬잖아!
- 아마 후회할걸
- But Chandler lent you money.
- And he would tell you it was a mistake.
집세랑 공과금 내려고 그래
Come on, I just.. I need it
for some rent and some other bills.
그래? 얼마나?
Well, how much?
- 2천 달러쯤?
- 2천 달러?
- Two thousand dollars?
내가 TV 스타라도
되는줄 아니?!
What do you think I am,
a soap opera star?
- 응
- 맞아! 난 스타야!
- Yeah.
- That's right, I am.
챈들러한테 말 안한다고
약속해
Promise me you'll never tell Chandler.
자존심이 상할거야
It'll really hurt his pride.
챈들러? 자존심?
Chandler? Pride?
자기가 자존심이 강하다고
생각하나봐, 되게 귀여워
I know, he thinks he has it.
It's really cute.
- 안녕
- Hi, you guys.
- Hey.
- 그 봉지는 뭐야?
- 엠마가 기어다니기 시작했잖아
- What's in the bag?
- You know how Emma started crawling?
집안에 아기한테 위험한게
많은것 같아서
I realized that this place
is very unsafe for a baby..
가게 가서 아기용 안전용품들
좀 사왔어
so I went to the store and I got some
stuff to baby-proof the apartment.
와, 웬 안전용품?
Oh, God, baby-proofing.
그럴필요 있어? 나 어렸을땐
Why is it such a big deal now?
You know, when I was a kid, it was like:
"아이쿠, 조이가 계단에서 굴렀네!"
"Whoops, Joey fell down the stairs."
"아이쿠, 조이가 또 감전됐네!"
그냥 그랬는데 말야
Or, "Whoops, Joey electrocuted
himself again."
아무튼..
이거 사람 불러서 설치할거니?
Anyway, are you going to get
a handyman to install this stuff?
아니, 내가 직접 할거야
No, I was just gonna do it myself.
- 네가 직접?
- 그래, 왜?
- You're gonna do it?
- Yeah. Why?
여자는 이런일 못할것 같아?
- You don't think a woman can do this?
- Women can. You can't.
아니, 다른 여자들은 하지
그런데 넌 못해
모니카, 조이한테
밥통이라고 전해줄래?
Monica, will you please tell Joey
that he is a pig.
넌 밥통이야!
넌 진짜 이거 못해
- You're a pig. And you can't do this.
- What?
뭐? 이런거 파는 가게도
나 혼자 찾았단 말야!
What? Come on, I found
the hardware store all by myself.
저앞에 조금만 가면 있잖아!
The store's right down the street.
저앞에 이런거
파는데가 있었어?
There is a hardware store
right down the street?
얘들아!
굉장한 소식이 있어!
Hey, you guys?
Okay, we've got great news.
- 피비랑 나, 동거하기로 했어요
- 축하해!
- Phoebe and I are moving in together.
- Congratulations.
정말 기대돼! 나 남자랑
같이 살아본적 없잖아!
I know, it's so exciting. You know,
I've never lived with a guy before.
여자랑 사는것과 똑같아
남잔 화장품을 훔쳐쓰지 않을 뿐이지
Well, it's just like living with a girl,
only they don't steal your makeup.
자기한테 여동생이 있었다면 이렇게
생겼을 거라며 장난칠땐 예외지만
Unless they're playing "This Is What
My Sister Would Look Like."
맞아, 내 여동생 별로 안예뻤어
Yeah, she's not so cute.
- 화장실 갔다올게요
- 쓰고 변기 뚜껑 내려놔요!
- I'm gonna go to the bathroom.
- Well, you put down the toilet seat.
네, 마님
Yes, dear.
- 그게 두사람 스타일이야?
- 너희 부부 흉내내는 거야?
- Is that a bit you guys do?
- Uh-huh. We're playing you two.
우리가 언제 그랬어?
우리 안그런다고 얘기해줘!
We don't do that.
Tell her we don't do that.
네, 마님
Yes, dear.
둘이 같이 산다니 굉장하다!
정말 축하해
I can't believe you're moving in together.
I'm happy for you guys.
남자 하나 정말 잘 골랐어
그 눈하며..
I mean, he's a great catch.
And those eyes..
난 과학자야
관찰력이 중요하다고
I'm a scientist. I observe.
너무 잘됐다!
큰 발전이야
Gosh, this is so exciting!
You guys are really moving along.
- 곧 청첩장 날아오겠네
- 앞서가지마
- I hear wedding bells.
- Monica, slow down, okay?
난 그저 함께
산다는 것만으로 좋으니까
I'm just excited to be living with him.
글쎄, 내가
You know, I mean, I don't know..
마이크와 결혼을 하게될까?
can I see someday being
married to Mike? Sure. Yeah.
우아하게 가슴에 포인트를 준
I could picture myself walking down
the aisle in a wedding dress..
웨딩드레스 입은
내모습 상상이 가
that highlights my breasts
in an obvious yet classy way.
우리 소피와 마이크 2세의
But do I want that house in Connecticut
near the good schools..
교육을 위해
코네티컷에서 살고 싶을까?
where Mike and I could send
little Sophie and Mike Jr.?
어머! 나 그러고 싶어!
Oh, my God, I do.
너한테 그렇게 평범한 면이
있는줄은 몰랐는걸?
- I had no idea you were so conventional.
- I know. I guess I am.
글쎄 말야!
나한테 그런면이 있나봐
나 볼보자동차에 애들 태우고
다니는 극성엄마 될거야!
Oh, my God, load up the Volvo,
I want to be a soccer mom.
- 갈래요?
- 그래요, 남친!
- You ready to go?
- Yeah, you bet, roomie.
'남편'이 아니구?
Don't you mean "groomie"?
자기야, 썰렁한 말장난은
나 하나로 족해
Honey, leave the terrible jokes to me.
- 무슨 소리예요?
- 아직
- What are you talking about?
- Please.
동거 시작도 안했는데
혼수그릇을 고르라고 하잖아요
We haven't even moved in yet, and
they have us picking out china patterns.
그릇 고르는 것도 재밌겠다!
China patterns!
간단하네
난 이런걸 못한다구?
This is easy. "Can't do this.."
와! 정말 못하네!
Wow, seriously. Can't do this.
- 조이
- 어서와
- Hey, Joe.
- Hey.
누구랑 같이 왔냐?
You here with somebody?
아니
No.
부탁좀 하자
대신 모니카한테는 비밀이야
Look, I need to ask you a favor,
and we can't tell Monica anything about it.
너 모니카한테 비밀 같은거
있으면 안되잖아!
- I thought you guys didn't have secrets.
- That will remain the official party line.
공식적인 기본방침은 변함없어
우리 부부 경제적으로
약간 문제가 생겼어
Look, Monica and I are having
a little financial trouble.
- 알아
- 알다니 무슨 소리야?
- Yeah, I know.
- What? What do you mean, you "know"?
짐작한다는 거지
I just figured it out, you know?
너 일도 안하는데
요즘 경제도 안좋잖아
I mean, you're not working,
and the economy is bad.
맞아
Oh, right.
이렇게 빨리 둘러대 보긴
처음이야!
That is the fastest I have ever thought.
그래서 말인데
Anyway..
돈좀 빌려줘
I need to borrow some money.
좋아, 얼마? 2천달러?
Oh, sure. Yeah, how much?
Two thousand dollars?
그래, 정확히 2천달러!
어떻게 알았어?
Yes, $2000 exactly.
How did you know that?
네 월급이 얼마였는지
너희 집세가 얼만지 대충 아니까
I know how much you used to make,
and I know how much your rent is.
그렇구나
Oh, okay.
나 신내렸나봐!
I am on fire.
정말 고맙다
Listen, this is really nice.
모니카한테 2천달러
수표 써줬어?
Did you write a check to Monica
for $2000?
모니카가 너한테 돈 빌렸니?
Did Monica borrow money from you?
- 그런셈이지
- 어떻게 이럴수가 있지!
- Kind of.
- I can't believe her.
모니카가 너한테
우리 돈 없다고 했니?
Did she tell you we were having
money problems?
아니, 아니, 너희들
돈 문제 때문이 아냐
No, no, no. It wasn't because
of your money problems.
쓸곳이 있다고 하더라구
It was for something for her.
무슨일?
What?
개인적인 일 같던데?
Something personal.
나한테 말도 안하고 2천 달러나
쓸일이 대체 뭔데?
What would she get for $2000
that she wouldn't tell me about?
실례합니다
Excuse me.
가슴성형수술
Boob job.
뭐? 말도 안돼
성형수술을 왜해?
What? That's ridiculous.
She doesn't need a boob job.
왜 나한텐 말안한거야?
Why wouldn't she tell me about it?
네가 싫어할까봐 그랬겠지
She was afraid you wouldn't be supportive.
- 싫어
- 딱 맞췄네
- I'm not.
- She knows you well.
내가 얘기했다는 말하면 안돼
비밀 지켜준다고 약속했다구
You can't tell her that you know.
I swore I wouldn't tell.
난 모니카 수술하는거 싫어!
미친 짓이야!
A boob job? She doesn't need that.
That's crazy.
그게 뭐가 미친 짓이야?
Well, it's not that crazy, okay?
가슴을 작게 만든다면
그게 미친 짓이지
Making them smaller,
that would be crazy.
포르노는 어디다 숨겨놨어요?
Hey, so where do you keep
your secret box of porn?
포르노 같은거 없어요
I don't have any porn.
내방 옷장 안에 있어요
Back of the closet in my bedroom.
아까 모니카가 '남편'
이라고 한말 있잖아요
Oh, hey, I wanted to ask you
about Monica's little "groomie" joke.
내가 '남친'이라고 부르니까
말장난한 거예요
Well, I think the reason people laughed
is that it's a play on the word "roomie."
그건 나도 알아요
세련된 말장난이었죠
I get the joke. Sophisticated as it was.
내가 하고 싶은 말은..
No, the thing I want to say is..
이런 얘기는 진작에
했어야 했는데..
Maybe we should've
talked about this before.
우리 함께 산다고 해서
청혼을 기대하는건 아니죠?
Us living together,
you're not expecting a proposal, right?
- 아뇨, 전혀요
- 됐어요
- Oh, no, no. Not at all.
- Okay.
이제 막 동거를 시작한 것뿐이니까
앞으로 어떻게 될지 보자구요
We're just moving in right now.
We'll see where it goes.
바로 그거예요
나한테 동거 그 이상은 없어요
Yeah, well, that's the thing.
For me, it's as far as it can ever go.
- 무슨 뜻이에요?
- 난 당신을..
- What do you mean?
- Look, Phoebe, I..
무척 사랑하지만
다시는 결혼하고 싶지 않아요
I love you very much.
But I never want to get married again.
- 어머!
- 내 첫번째 결혼이..
- Wow.
- It's just, my first marriage was..
완전한 실패였기 때문에
결혼에 대한 믿음을 잃었어요
you know, such a disaster that
I kind of lost faith in the whole idea.
- 그렇게 나빴어요?
- 거의 막판에는
- Was it that bad?
- At one point, near the end..
- 아내가 고의적으로 자기 배설물을..
- 그만! 정말 나빴군요
- she deliberately defecated on my..
- Okay, well, that's bad. Yeah.
상대가 다르면 결혼생활도
다르지 않을까요?
But don't you think it might be
different with someone else? Perhaps..
금발에 언제나 화장실에서만
볼일보는 여자라면요
a blond who always
uses the toilet?
딱 한번 바다에 싼적 있어요
Except for once in the ocean.
문제는 상대가 아녜요
Look, it's not about who I would marry.
처음 결혼할때 영원할 거라
확신했지만 내가 틀렸더라구요
I was certain the first time I got married
it'd last forever. I was wrong.
- 하지만..
- 피비 때문이 아녜요
- But, it just..
- Look, Phoebe, it's not about you.
내가 다시는 결혼하고
싶지 않아서 그래요
I just never want to get married again.
미안해요
I'm sorry.
괜찮아요? 아니면 우리 동거
다시 생각해야 할거예요
Are you okay with that? If not, maybe
us moving in together isn't the best idea.
나도 결혼 같은거
하고싶지 않아요
No. Oh, I definitely don't
want to get married.
마이크가 정말로 결혼하기 싫은지
확인하고 싶었을 뿐이에요, 휴!
I just wanted to make sure
you didn't want to, too.
만약 같이 살다가
마이크 마음이 변하면
Because if we move in
and you start changing your mind..
골치 아파질 테니까요
there is gonna be
hell to pay, mister.
- 결코 그런일 없어요
- 네! 알았어요!
- Trust me. I will never..
- Yeah, I get that. Yeah.
결국 사람 부르기로 했구나
Hi. So you gave in
and decided to call someone?
그래, 내가 뭘 믿고 덤볐나 몰라
젓가락질도 못하는 주제에
Yeah. I don't know who I was kidding.
I can barely use chopsticks.
- 다 됐습니다
- 고마워요
- You're all set.
- Oh, thank you so much.
잠깐만요! 아저씨
Wait. You forgot your..
장난감 가져 가셔야죠
game.
고맙습니다
Thank you.
- 레이첼, 이거 내 스웨터 아냐?
- 맞아
- Rach, is this my sweater?
- Yeah.
팔 한쪽이 왜이래?
What happened to the sleeve?
좀먹었나?
Moths?
안녕? 황금비율의 완벽한 몸매를
자랑하는 우리 마누라도 있네!
Hey, Rach. There she is,
my perfectly proportioned wife.
나 보지마!
난 챈들러 농담 이해 못하니까
Don't look at me.
I never get his jokes.
- 고마워
- 나한테 고맙다니!
- Thank you?
- No, no. Don't thank me.
나야말로 고맙지, 난 당신 모습
단 한군데도 바뀌지 않았으면 좋겠어
Thank you. Do you know there is not
one thing I would change about you?
단 한군데도!
두군데는
Not one single thing.
And definitely not..
더 말할것도 없지!
two single things.
정말 이상하게 구네, 침대로 가고
싶다는 거야? 아님 뭐 잘못한거 있어?
Okay, you're being weird. Do you want
sex, or did you do something bad?
아냐, 자기 모습 그대로가 좋다구!
No. No. No. I just love
the way you look. I am warm..
자기 몸매는 날 흥분시켜
for your form.
그냥 평범하게 예쁘다고 하면 될걸
Okay, you know the old classics like,
you know, "You look nice"?
왜 오버하고 그래?
They're still okay.
예쁘다는건 얼굴을 말하는 거고
But "you look nice" could mean
that I'm saying, "Your face looks nice."
난 자기몸매를 칭찬하고 싶어
I want to compliment your body.
나라면 절대 바꾸지 않을 거야
I mean, I wouldn't change it at all.
특히 어떤 부분이든 크게
만드는 일은 절대 안할거라구!
And more specifically, I wouldn't
want anything to get any bigger.
- 알았어
- 자기도
- Okay.
- I mean..
내몸의 어떤 부분이
커지는건 바라지 않잖아?
you wouldn't want any part of me
to get any bigger, would you?
대답하지마
Don't answer that.
저렇게 이상하게 구는건
보다보다 처음 본다
Just when you thought that dude
couldn't get any weirder.
글쎄 말야, 내몸이 커지는 것에
대해 왜 저렇게 걱정하지?
Why do you think he was so worried
about me getting bigger?
왜그런 생각을 하게 됐을까?
I don't know.
I mean, what brought that on?
맞다! 우리 아기 가지려고
노력중이잖아!
Oh, my God. You know what,
we're trying to get pregnant..
임신하면 내 몸매가 변할 테니까
그걸 걱정하나봐!
so he's probably starting to freak out
that my body's gonna change.
- 설마! 정말 그럴까?
- 너도 들었잖아!
- You think that's what it is?
- You heard him.
"커지면 안돼! 지금 그대로가 좋아!"
"No bigger. You're perfect.
Just don't get any bigger."
"커지면 안돼"? 고등학교때
레슬링 코치가 하던말 같아!
My God, he sounded just like
my high-school wrestling coach.
- 챈들러랑 얘기좀 해야겠어
- 네가 안하면 나라도 할거야!
- I'm gonna have to talk to Chandler.
- Yeah. If you don't, I will.
몸매는 변할 수밖에 없어!
가슴도 커지고
Of course your body's gonna change.
Your breasts are gonna get bigger..
엉덩이도 커지고!
your ass is gonna get bigger..
방광조절 기능도 약해지고..
you're gonna lose bladder control.
오! 사람이 완전히 변한다니까!
God, it's just such a magical time.
안녕, 결혼에 대해
물어보고 싶은게 있어
Hi. Listen, I wanted to ask you
something about marriage.
이젠 날 찾아다니면서까지
놀리는 거니?
Now you're seeking me out
to make jokes?
다들 모여 있을때도 모자라서
집까지 찾아와서 놀리려구?
I mean, I can see if we're all hanging
out, but to come to my home..
아냐, 정말 결혼에 대한
네 생각을 듣고 싶어서 그래
No, I really want to know
how you feel about it.
- 왜?
- 마이크가 자긴
- Why?
- Mike doesn't ever want to get married.
절대로 결혼 안한대
- 절대로?
- 절대로
- Never?
- Never.
저런!
그래도 같이 살거야?
Wow. Are you still gonna
move in with him?
그러고 싶긴 한데.. 결혼 따위
별거 아니지? 그렇게 말해줘
I want to, but I wanted you to tell me
that marriage really isn't that big a deal.
안해도 후회하지 않을 거라고
결혼은 골치 아픈 거라고 말야
You know, that I won't be missing out
on anything. That marriage stinks.
그럼! 골치 아프지
Yeah, marriage stinks.
결혼하면 그날로 남자는 살찌고
I mean, if you want to see a man gain
weight and a woman stop shaving..
여자는 화장을 안해
get them married.
- 정말 그렇게 생각하는건 아니지?
- 맞아, 미안해
- That's not how you really feel, is it?
- No, I'm sorry.
네가 듣고싶은 말은 아니겠지만
어쩌겠어? 난 결혼하는거 좋아!
I know it's not what you want to hear,
but I can't help it. I love marriage.
진심이니, 이혼장이?
Seriously, you?
"Divorce-o"?
이왕이면 "이혼전문가"라고 불러줘
훨씬 멋있잖아?
If you have to call me a name, I'd prefer
"Ross, the Divorcer." It's just cooler.
내가 비록 결혼에
실패하긴 했지만..
Look, I know my marriages
didn't exactly work out..
다른 사람과 그런 깊은
관계를 갖는다는게 좋아
but, you know, I loved being
that committed to another person.
캐롤이 레즈비언이 되기 전까지
우리 정말 좋았어
And Carol and I had some good times
before she became a lesbian.
그후에도 한번은 좋았고
And once afterward.
도움이 못돼서 미안해
Anyway, I'm sorry.
괜찮아
그게 네 진심인걸
It's okay. That's how you feel.
하지만 같이 사는것도
정말 좋을거야!
But, come on, I mean,
living together will be great.
두사람 잘 맞잖아
또 넌 마이크를 사랑하고
I mean, you guys have so much fun.
And you love Mike.
- 그건 사실이야
- 아까는
- I do love Mike.
- Yeah, see?
같이 살게 됐다고
신나서 좋아했잖아
And you were so excited about
moving in together before..
그럴만해!
동거도 굉장한 거라구!
and you know what, you should be.
It's a big deal.
네말이 맞는것 같아
Yeah, I guess you're right.
고마워
도움이 됐어
Yeah, thanks. This helped. Thanks.
긴급 구조대 이혼전문가!
The Divorcer to the rescue.
- 하나도 안멋있다
- 내 생각에도 그래
- It's not cooler.
- Yeah, I just heard it.
레이첼?
Rach?
레이첼!
Rachel?!
나더러 아무것도
하지 말라는 거야?!
So I can't do anything I like?!
정말 믿을수가 없어
Unbelievable.
네가 임신하길 바라면서
몸이 변하는건 인정 못한다는게
Chandler wants you to have a baby, but
he doesn't want your body to change.
챈들러는 뭐가 그리 완벽하다구
It's not like he's so perfect.
- 그래도 내 남편이야
- 알았어
- Hey, that's my husband.
- All right.
문제는 하나씩 해결하자
Let's solve one problem at a time.
안녕, 레이첼?
Hey, Rach.
안녕, 완벽한 미모?
아무것도 바꾸지마! 한군데도!
Perfection.
Wouldn't change a thing. Not a thing.
- 챈들러?
- 왜?
- Honey?
- Yeah?
얘기좀 해
About that.
- 내몸은 바뀔거야
- 자긴 그럴 필요없어!
- I'm going to change.
- Yes, but, honey, you don't have to.
내몸은 커질거야
I'm gonna get bigger.
난 자기 가슴
Honey, I..
지금 그대로가 좋아
I love your breasts the way they are.
으, 순 독재자!
Fascist.
자기가 좋아하건 말건
내 가슴은 커질거야
My breasts are gonna get bigger
whether you like it or not.
가슴뿐만이 아닌걸?
내 엉덩이도 커질거라구
And it's not just my breasts.
My ass is gonna get bigger too.
엉덩이도?!
Your ass?!
손이랑 발도 커질테니 두고봐
And don't be surprised if her hands
and her feet get bigger too.
- 그런것도 있어?
- 그건 말하자면 다 한세트란 말야!
- They do that?
- It's kind of a package deal.
맙소사!
대체 왜그러고 싶은건데?
God, why? Why would you want to
do that to yourself?
자기도 원하는거 아니었어?
I thought it was something
that we both wanted.
자기가 정 원한다면
가슴은 받아들일수 있어
If it means that much to you, I may be
able to get onboard with the boobs..
하지만 커다란 엉덩이에
발까지?
but the giant ass
and the big clown feet?
오, 챈들러!
Oh, my God, Chandler.
그런것도 못견디면서
나중에 병원가서
If you can't handle this,
what will you be like in the hospital..
그 피에, 비명에, 아기 나오는건
어떻게 견딜거야?
with the blood and screaming and the
little person that's shooting out of her?
뭐?
What?
조이, 왜 챈들러한테 모니카가
가슴수술 할거라고 했어?
Joey, why did you tell Chandler
that Monica was getting a boob job?
사실이니까!
Because she is.
내가 너한테 돈 빌린거
챈들러도 알아
- Chandler knows I borrowed the money.
- For your boob job.
그래, 수술하려고 빌렸잖아
- 조이!
- 다 끝났어! 그만해!
- Joe..
- It's over.
뭐야, 내돈이 4천 달러나 나갔는데
아무도 가슴 커지는 사람이 없어?
Okay, so I'm out $4000 and
nobody's boobs are getting any bigger?
이건 어떻게 생각해?
"이혼 기동대, 로스"
Hey. Hey, what do you guys think
about this: Ross, the Divorce Force.
- 좀 낫다
- 그래?
- Better.
- Yeah?
멋있는데요?
Very cool.
피비? 지난번에 나한테
상담하러 와줘서 기뻤어
Hey, Phoebe? You know, I'm really glad
you came to talk to me the other day..
- 내가 도움이 됐으면 좋겠다
- 도움이 됐어
- and I hope I was a little helpful.
- Yeah, you were helpful.
- 고마워
- 잘됐다
- Yeah. No, thank you.
- Good. Good.
더 생각해보니까
이런 생각이 들더라
Because the more I thought about it,
the more I realized..
결혼이란 게 너한테
꼭 필요한건 아닌것 같아
I don't think marriage is necessarily
the right path for you.
무슨 뜻이야?
What do you mean?
너 지난번에 카페에서
I know the other day
in the coffeehouse..
극성엄마 운운하면서
흥분했었지?
you were all caught up
in the whole soccer-mom thing..
그런데 그게 정말 네 모습일까?
볼보자동차 탄 네 모습 상상이 가?
but is that really you? I mean, can you
honestly picture yourself in a Volvo?
그차는 너무 상자곽 같아
They are awfully boxy.
나같은 사람이나 안정감과 확신을
좋아하지, 넌 안그렇잖아
People like me like stability
and security. You don't.
그래서 너를 존경하는 거야
And that's what's so incredible
about you.
넌 열정적인 삶을
살고 있으니깐
You got this wild and crazy life.
잘은 모르겠지만 넌 결혼생활에
곧 싫증이 날거야, 너무 평범하니까
I mean, I don't know, you'd be so bored
with marriage. I mean, it's so normal.
그래
Yeah.
나도 도와줄까?
Hey, can I help?
계단 4층을 올라와서
사나운 개가 덤벼드는 와중에
Well, we climbed up four flights of stairs,
maneuvered a narrow hallway..
좁은 복도를 지나왔지, 하지만 마지막
남은 1미터가 제일 힘들것 같긴 하다
dodged a rabid pit bull. But these last
three feet are where it gets really tricky.
너 가끔은
말 너무 심하게 해!
You know, sometimes your words,
they hurt.
이거 어디다 놓을까?
Hey, where do you guys want this?
빨리 말해!
이거 진짜 무거워!
Yeah, seriously,
because this is really heavy.
난 잡는 시늉만 해서 안무겁지만
얘들은 무거울 거야
I mean, not for me, because I'm only
pretending to hold it, but for these guys.
결혼에 대해서 마지막으로 물을게요
가능성이 없어요? 전혀?
Just one last time on the marriage thing.
There's no wiggle room? None at all?
전혀 없어요
피비도 결혼은 싫다면서요?
No, but you don't want to
get married either, right?
맞아요
Right.
실은 결혼하고 싶어요
Except that I do want to get married.
그런 얘기라면 아까
트럭에서 하면 좋았잖아!
Couldn't have had this conversation
down at the truck, huh?
결혼하고 싶다구요?
What? You want to get married?
언젠가는
Someday.
아이고, 팔 빠지겠다!
And.. hernia.
내 인생 평범하진 않았지만
뭔가 빠졌다고 느낀 적도 없어요
I haven't had a normal life. And I never
felt like I was missing out on anything.
하지만 이젠 나도 정상적인
삶을 살아보고 싶어요
But it feels like now it's my turn
to have some of the regular stuff.
결혼하고 싶다면
왜 진작 말하지 않았어요?
Why didn't you say something before?
결혼을 얼만큼 하고 싶은지
나도 잘 몰랐거든요
I didn't know how much I wanted it. And
I love you, and I wanted to live with you.
그리고 마이크를 사랑하고
마이크와 함께 있고 싶었어요
나도 마찬가지예요
그러니까 우리 같이 살아요
I want to live with you too.
I mean, let's do that.
그럴수 없을것 같아요
But I don't think I can.
앞으로 무슨일이 생길지 모른채
함께 사는건 몰라도
It was okay to move in when
I didn't know what was gonna happen.
아무일도 생기지 않을 거라는걸
알면서 동거할수는 없어요
But I can't move in knowing nothing
is ever gonna happen.
내가 뭐랬어
쿠션부터 갖고 올라오자고 했지?
I said to bring the cushions
up first, but no.
한번 해보자구요
피비 생각이 변할수도 있잖아요?
Can we at least try living together? You
might change your mind about marriage.
마이크의 생각도 변할까요?
Are you gonna change yours?
아뇨
No.
나도 마찬가지예요
Me neither.
나와 같은걸 원하는 사람과
함께 있고 싶어요
I think I need to be with someone
who wants what I want.
이렇게 끝날순 없어요
But I don't want this to end.
나도 이렇게 끝내고 싶지 않아요
No, I don't want it to end either.
우리가 이렇게 끝나다니!
I can't believe this is gonna end.
내 물건 챙길게요
I guess I'll have my stuff picked up.
그래요
Yeah. Okay.
그럼..
Okay, so..
잘있어요
Goodbye.
- 잘가요, 마이크!
- 안녕, 마이크!
- Take it easy, Mike.
- Bye, Mike.
속 많이 상하지?
I'm so sorry, Phoebe.
우리도 가슴아프다
We're all sorry.
좋은 쪽으로 생각해, 최소한 이 흉측한
소파를 집에 안들여놔도 되잖아
Look on the bright side. At least you
won't have to live with this ugly chair.
이미 들어와 있군
That was here already, huh?
사랑해
I love you.
됐다! 성공이야!
I did it! I did it!
좋았어!
All right.
되는대로 다 꺼내가야지!
I'd better take all I can carry.
다시는 못열지도 모르잖아!
Who knows when I'll be able
to get in here again, huh?